The Mountain Men is a adventure, western, drama film directed by Richard Lang.
The story concerns two grizzled mountain men -- Bill Tyler and Henry
Frapp -- during the dying days of the fur-trapping era.
The plot begins when Running Moon runs away from her abusive husband
Heavy Eagle and comes across the two seedy fur trappers.
The mountain men take her in, unaware that Heavy Eagle has
dispatched an army of Indian braves to reclaim her.
Bill Tyler, played by Charlton Heston.
Henry Frapp, played by Brian Keith.
Running Moon, played by Victoria Racimo.
Heavy Eagle, played by Stephen Macht.
La Bont, played by Seymour Cassel.
Medicine Wolf, played by David Ackroyd.
The Mountain Men is a 1980 American adventure Western film directed by
Richard Lang and starring Charlton Heston and Brian Keith.
Heston's son, Fraser Clarke Heston, wrote the screenplay.
The film explores themes of native american, frontier,
frontier justice, 19th century, mountain man.
The tone is emotional.